Ubaidullah Ganie

Address: Akhran Kulgam, Jammu and Kashmir, India (192231).

Date of Birth: 03, March, 1990.

Mobile: +91 9906404836 Email: <u>imubaid@live.com</u>

GIS Analyst with 4 years 10 months of experience in the field of GIS and Remote Sensing. M.Sc. in Geo-Informatics and Remote Sensing. An enthusiastic individual with a desire to learn, seeking opportunity to work within a challenging and stimulating environment that provide opportunities to enrich my knowledge and to utilize my efficiency to the maximum extent possible.

Major projects

Monitoring of Wular Lake Phase-I.

Client name: Wular conservation and management authority.

Duration: January 2016 to March 2017

Empowering Panchayati Raj Institutes Spatially

Client name: NRSC

Duration: April 2017 to February 2019

FASAL (Forecasting Agricultural output using Space,

Agro-meteorology and Land based observations)

Client name: Ministry of Agriculture Duration: November 2019 to Present

Work experience

Mahalanobis National Crop Forecast centre Krishi Vistar Sadan, Pusa Campus New Delhi. Analyst Level Personnel, FASAL Project.

MNCFC New Delhi.

From November 2019 to Present

J&K Dept. of environment, ecology and Remote Sensing Bemina J&K India. GIS Analyst, 'Empowering Panchayati Raj Institutes Spatially (EPRIS)' JKDEARS Bemina.

From April 2017 to February 2019

J&K Dept. of environment, ecology and Remote Sensing Bemina J&K India. Field cum digitizing Assistant, 'Wular Conservation and Management Authority (WUCMA)' JKDEARS Bemina. From January 2016 to March 2017

EDUCATION

Faculty of Science, Department of Earth Sciences, University of Kashmir 2015.

Post-Graduation in Remote sensing and GIS (Geoinformatics) with 63% (Grade-I), With Thesis title as: Assessing the Glacier Dynamics in Suru Basin Ladakh Using Remotely Sensed Data From 2000-2014.

Bachelor of Science, Govt. Degree College for Boys Anantnag, Kashmir 2012. Bachelor of Science (First Division) with Physics Mathematics and Geography.

Regional Conference on Geoinformatics for Early Warning of Disasters with Special Emphasis on NE Region September 18-19, 2014 (Organized by Indian Society of Geomatics)

TECHNICAL SKILLS.

GIS and Remote Sensing Softwares: Arc GIS, ERDAS Imagine, SNAP, QGIS, Global Mapper 11, Map Window GIS, Shape to Earth and Google Earth Engine

Ubald

Microsoft Office: Ms Word, Ms Excel, Ms Power Point etc.

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python (Basics)

Data base management